alright let's get started welcome to the
好吧，让我们开始吧，欢迎来到
session on designing functional programs
设计功能程序会议
my name is Venkat Subramanyam we're
我叫Venkat Subramanyam，我们是
going to talk about how do we approach
谈论我们如何处理
some of the concerns we normally have
我们通常有的一些担忧
when it comes to designing functional
在设计功能时
applications just to quickly set the
应用程序只是为了快速设置
stage where this kind of talk came from
这种讲话来自的阶段
I've been giving talks on programming
我一直在谈编程
with functional style in Java for a
Java中的功能样式
quite a number of years now and almost
现在已经有很多年了
always when I finished my talk I would
每当我说完话，我都会
have people come up to me and ask some
有人来找我，问一些
questions and there was a very common
问题，有一个非常普遍的
theme of questions that happened almost
几乎发生的问题的主题
every single time I gave a talk it's
我每次演讲都
like oh I've heard this question so many
就像哦，我听过很多这个问题
times and so I said well that really
时代，所以我说的很好
means
手段
it deserves a talk on its own so I kind
它值得一个演讲，所以我很客气
of grabbed some of those questions and
抓住了其中一些问题，
create a talk out of it so I'd really
创建一个演讲，所以我真的
want to talk about how do we really
想谈谈我们如何真正
approach you know designing some
你知道设计一些方法
functional systems also what are some of
功能系统还有哪些
the deficiencies of the functional style
函数式风格的不足
of programming in Java where it may fall
用Java进行编程的地方
a little flat and where we may have to
有点平，我们可能需要
do a little bit different this is not
做一点不同，这不是
about functional programming in general
关于一般的函数式编程
this is pretty much about how do we deal
这与我们如何处理有关
with this in Java because the tools we
在Java中与此相关，因为我们使用的工具
use often constrain what we can do while
经常限制我们在做什么的同时
there are concepts and theories and
有概念和理论，
practices out there we may not be able
练习，我们可能无法
to do all of that the way we want it to
以我们希望的方式完成所有这些工作
do depending on what tool and
取决于哪种工具
environment and language and framework
环境，语言和框架
and libraries we use so this is pretty
和我们使用的库，这很漂亮
much about the world that most of us in
关于我们大多数人所处的世界
this room live in which is hey we're
这个房间住的嘿我们
programming in Java we have adopted Java
Java编程，我们采用了Java
8 we're programming in functional style
8我们以函数式风格进行编程
but how do we really approach it that's
但是我们如何真正做到这一点
kind of what I really want to focus on
我真正想要关注的是
in this talk so in terms of functional
从功能上讲
programming so what is really functional
编程，什么才是真正的功能
programming well we are trying to do a
编程很好，我们正在尝试做一个
function decomposition that's what we're
函数分解就是我们要做的
really trying to do one of the things
真的试图做一件事情
that really frustrates me when some
这让我感到非常沮丧
people who are practicing functional
练习功能的人
programming go out and say gosh this is
编程出去，说天哪，这是
great we don't have to do objects
太好了，我们不必做任何事情
anymore to me that's trying to throw the
对我来说，这正试图把
baby with the bathwater right I don't
婴儿洗澡水，我不
have a problem with object-oriented
面向对象有问题
programming I have problem with the way
编程我的方式有问题
people use object-oriented programming
人们使用面向对象的编程
so the problem is not in oh the problem
所以问题不在哦
is and how it is being used by a lot of
是以及如何被许多人使用
people and and I strongly have benefited
人们和我都从中受益匪浅
from object into programming so
从对象到编程
I don't want to throw it away but in
我不想扔掉它，但是在
that regard I want to look at it a
那个方面我想看一下
little differently so what am I really
有点不同，我到底是什么
trying to do when I try to program in
当我尝试编程时尝试做
function style what am I really
我真正的函数式风格是什么
approaching so if you really look back
如果你真的回头
in about twenty years of Java
在Java的20年左右
programming we all can agree that we be
编程我们都可以同意我们
in programming in object-oriented
面向对象编程中
systems right so we've been doing
系统正确，所以我们一直在做
object-oriented programming so that's
面向对象的程序设计
that's kind of summarizes that's what
就是这样的总结
we've been doing but let's be really
我们一直在做，但让我们成为现实
honest about it there's nobody who has
老实说，没有人拥有
ever written object-oriented code with
曾经用
only objects it's impossible to do that
只有对象是不可能做到的
because when you create objects what is
因为当您创建对象时，什么是
the next thing you do you create methods
接下来要做的是创建方法
and fields maybe and then when you
和田野也许然后当你
create methods what do you do well how
创建方法你擅长什么
are the methods going to be implemented
将要实施的方法
well we gotta write some code for
好吧，我们要写一些代码
implementing the methods so what we've
实现方法，所以我们已经
been really doing honestly is not
真正做到诚实不是
object-oriented programming we just keep
我们只保留面向对象的编程
saying it what we've been doing really
说这是我们一直在做的
is imperative plus object-oriented in
势在必行加上面向对象
all honesty right because that's what
所有诚实的权利，因为那是什么
we've been really doing imperative plus
我们一直在做当务之急
object of the programming is what we've
编程的目的是
been doing all these years because the
这些年来一直在做，因为
methods we write and how we work with
我们编写的方法以及如何使用
multiple objects all of them have been
多个对象都已经
imperative and and to me there are parts
势在必行，对我而言，这部分内容
of oh that really is bad but there are
哦，那真的很糟糕，但是有
parts of oh that is very powerful very
哦的那部分非常强大
useful and I don't want to let go of
有用，我不想放手
them that's just my personal choice I
他们只是我个人的选择
know I might my anger is not an object
知道我可能不会发怒
into programming right but so the
进入编程，但是
question is what are we really trying to
问题是我们到底在尝试什么
get to well where I'm gonna still
到我仍然要去的地方康复
continue doing object into programming
继续做对象编程
but I'm gonna do it with functional
但我要用功能
decomposition plus object or in the
分解加对象或在
programming so all I'm interested really
编程，所以我真的很感兴趣
here is replacing that part not the
这里是替换那部分而不是
right side because the right side is not
右边，因为右边不是
my main problem the sure it can be done
我的主要问题是可以做到的
in a very poor way I'm not saying that
我不是很可恶
people don't do in a poor way but if I
人们做事不坏，但是如果我
do oh oh in a really good way then my
哦，哦，哦，那真的很好
problem is not to throw it oh oh my
问题是不要扔它哦哦我的
problem is to throw out the imperative
问题是当务之急
style or at least replace it with a
样式或至少将其替换为
functional style so in Java
Java中的功能样式
today and other languages for example
今天和其他语言
you know Ruby and Scala and groovy just
你知道Ruby，Scala和groovy
Java is not the only language that does
Java不是唯一的语言
this a lot of different languages you
这很多不同的语言
can actually use object oriented
可以实际使用面向对象
decomposition
分解
can mix it with functional decomposition
可以将其与功能分解混合
as well and you can benefit from best of
也可以从中受益
the both words and that is one of the
这两个词，这是其中之一
really rewarding things for us to do so
为我们这样做真的很有意义
so uh what I'm trying to do over the
所以呃我正在努力做的
years is really get better at this part
这几年真的好起来了
where can I apply object into
我可以在哪里应用对象
programming and where can I apply
编程，我可以在哪里申请
functional programming and put them to
功能编程并将其放入
really good use and benefit from each
真的很好用，并从中受益
one of them because I find value in both
其中之一是因为我在两者中都找到了价值
of them and of course on occasion I do
他们，当然我有时候
have to admit I do use imperative style
必须承认我确实使用命令式风格
of programming also to me these are just
对我来说，编程也只是
tools I'm not biased towards one two
我不偏向于一二的工具
versus the other
与另一个
I prefer functional style programming
我更喜欢函数式编程
where it makes sense where my life is
我的生活在哪里有意义
easier where I can actually benefit from
更容易让我真正受益的地方
it but there are times when may be an
它，但有时可能会
imperative style is better for the
命令式的风格更适合
problem at hand and I don't mind really
眼前的问题，我真的不介意
using that in that particular context so
在那个特定的上下文中使用它
so in that sense what is really
所以从这个意义上说，真正的是
functional programming you know espouse
你知道的函数式编程
what does it really provide well the
它真正提供了什么？
very first thing we hear about
我们听到的第一件事
functional programming when you start
开始时进行功能编程
reading over function programming will
阅读功能编程将
start learning about it what do they
开始了解它是什么
tell us the first thing they tell you is
告诉我们他们告诉你的第一件事是
hey you should not do any mutability
嘿，你不应该做任何改变
right assignment less programming is
权利分配少的编程是
extremely important don't do assignments
非常重要的是不要做作业
don't change anyway variables and values
无论如何不要更改变量和值
there are a good number of languages I
我有很多语言
classify those languages as so I
将这些语言分类为
classify languages into a couple of
将语言分为几类
different ways within this context I
在这种情况下，我有不同的方式
call them as purely functional
称它们为纯功能
programming languages languages and and
编程语言语言和
then of course there are languages what
那当然有语言
I call as a hybrid functional languages
我称之为混合功能语言
just like in object-oriented programming
就像在面向对象的编程中一样
you had fully object-oriented languages
你有完全面向对象的语言
but you also had hybrid object-oriented
但是你也有混合的面向对象
languages one example of hybrid optical
语言混合光学的一个例子
language was C++ even though people will
语言是C ++，即使人们愿意
argue whether it's object-oriented or
争论它是面向对象的还是
not but but I'm not really interested in
不是，但是我并不真正感兴趣
that argument it is in hybrid language
这种说法是混合语言
as for some concern because I could do
至于一些担心，因为我可以
no objects at all in it right pure C pro
完全没有对象，对，纯C pro
code in it if I want to or I can mix and
如果需要，可以在其中进行编码，也可以混合使用
match it whereas if you take a very very
匹配它，而如果您采取非常非常
purely object-oriented language it will
纯粹的面向对象语言
not all of you to really have anything
并不是所有人真正拥有任何东西
outside of objects it'll enforce that
在对象之外，它将强制执行
and objects are really becoming the
对象真的变成了
paradigm in that case of course you're
在这种情况下，范式当然是
still being imperative but but they're
仍然势在必行，但他们
not entirely procedural on the outside
外部程序不完全
much like this there are certain
很像这样
languages which are purely functional
纯粹是功能性的语言
programming languages these languages
编程语言这些语言
will not allow you to
不会让你
anything period there is no syntax for
任何时期都没有语法
modifying a variable once you create it
创建变量后对其进行修改
you can spend hours and days together
你可以一起度过数小时和数天
there is no way you can change it I
我无法改变它
teach a course on programming languages
教授编程语言课程
and in the in that course I usually use
在那个过程中，我通常使用
about eight languages but my students
大约八种语言，但我的学生
are way better than me
比我好
collectively we use about 20 or 25
我们总共使用大约20或25
languages in the course it's very
课程中的语言非常
rewarding course to teach because I come
奖励课程，因为我来
out learning a lot from this course but
从这个课程中学到很多东西，但是
in one semester a student with about you
一个学期有一个关于你的学生
know 15 years of experience came to me
知道我有15年的经验
and said you know I've used these
说你知道我用过这些
languages but I actually like a purely
语言，但我实际上很喜欢
functional language better than a hybrid
功能语言比混合语言更好
functional language he said I said why
他说的功能语言我说为什么
do you say that and and and the reasons
你这么说和以及原因
he gave could be taken in two ways and
他给的方式有两种
he said the reason is when I sit down to
他说原因是当我坐下来
write code I come from imperative style
写代码来自命令式风格
a background object of silent background
静音背景的背景对象
when it's down to write code when a
当写代码的时候
language is hybrid I struggle with it
语言是混合的，我为此苦苦挣扎
for 15 minutes I cannot figure out how
15分钟我无法弄清楚
to do it I quietly go back to my old
要做到这一点，我安静地回到我的旧
ways of doing things and the language
处事方式和语言
quietly lets me do it on the other hand
另一方面让我安静地做
this purely functional language beats me
这种纯粹的功能性语言击败了我
down right it takes me and beats me on
没错，这需要我并击败我
my head and says it's my way or the
我的头说这是我的方式
highway and I cry I complain I curse and
公路，我哭泣，我抱怨我诅咒，
seven hours later I'm still stuck and
七个小时后，我仍然陷于困境，
then I go take a break come back the
然后我去休息一下
next day and finally things begin to
第二天，最后事情开始
work and after all this frustration I'm
工作，毕竟这让我沮丧
beginning to see the light of how to do
开始看到如何做的光
this so he said from that point of view
所以他从那个角度说
I really like languages that beat me
我真的很喜欢打败我的语言
down and tell me this is the way to do
下来告诉我这是方法
it I said that's exactly the reason why
我说那正是原因
I also prefer hybrid languages because
我也更喜欢混合语言，因为
when I'm at work my boss is gonna beat
当我上班时我的老板会被击败
me even harder right when I don't get
当我不明白的时候我会更加努力
the word done so I'm really happy to say
这个词完成了，所以我真的很高兴地说
you know what this purity is all great
你知道这种纯度是什么
but I've got this in production now we
但是我现在已经在生产中了
can come back and refactor it I'm a
可以回来重构它，我是
really pragmatic person rather than
真正务实的人而不是
being a perfectionist yeah I really want
是一个完美主义者，是的，我真的想要
to do good things but at the end of the
做善事，但在最后
day I still have to you know continue
那天我仍然要你知道继续
releasing products as well that's kind
也要发布产品
of the reason why I like these kinds of
我之所以喜欢这些类型的原因
languages because they do give you an
语言，因为它们确实为您提供了
escape route when you're stuck with
当你陷入困境时的逃生路线
something so in that regard there are
在这方面有一些东西
some languages that don't have
一些没有的语言
mutability at all available so here
完全可变，所以这里
surely one of favor immutability but
肯定是不变性之一，但
that's one of the things that function
那是起作用的事情之一
programming languages really espouse the
编程语言真的支持
other thing is
另一件事是
higher order functions what in the world
高阶函数的功能
is higher order functions well let's
高阶函数很好吗
think about this for a minute again in
再考虑一分钟
the context of Java and what we've been
Java的上下文以及我们一直以来的经历
used to
过去
what are what have we been doing so far
到目前为止我们一直在做什么
we may pass object to object to
我们可能将对象传递给
functions I am I'm purposefully not
我不是我故意的功能
using the world method so just clearly
使用世界方法，所以很清楚
to get it get it out of the way to me a
得到它，把它弄走给我
method it's just a function a method is
方法，它只是一个函数
a function that has association to a
与...关联的功能
class or an object so a function could
类或对象，因此函数可以
be a free-standing function a method is
成为独立功能的一种方法是
a function that's tied to a class or to
与类或类相关的功能
our to an instance so I'm just going to
我们到一个实例，所以我只是要
use the word function in general we may
通常使用单词function，我们可能
pass a object to a function we may
将对象传递给函数
create a create after all object within
在所有对象之后创建一个create
function so here we can do that too we
功能，所以在这里我们也可以做到这一点
are already doing that in languages like
已经以类似
Java and then finally we may return
Java，最后我们可能会返回
object from function I'm not trying to
我不想要的功能对象
be grammatically correct here for good
在语法上要正确正确
reasons so so this is what we've been
原因，所以这就是我们去过的地方
doing we're used to doing this what is a
这样做我们已经习惯了
higher-order function after all
毕竟高阶函数
higher-order function is where we may
高阶函数是我们可以在哪里
pass a function to a function we may
将功能传递给我们可能会使用的功能
create a function within a function we
在函数中创建函数
may return a function from a function so
可能从一个函数返回一个函数，所以
that's basically what makes a function a
这基本上就是使函数成为
higher-order function is that we can
高阶函数是我们可以
compose functions using other functions
使用其他功能组合功能
to put things together so we are using
把东西放在一起，所以我们正在使用
higher-order functions to build stuff
高阶函数来构建东西
around it so a higher-order functions
围绕它，因此具有更高阶的功能
give us the ability you can still take
给我们您仍然可以接受的能力
objects as parameters you can still
对象仍然可以作为参数
return objects as results but in
返回对象作为结果，但是
addition you could also work with
此外，您还可以使用
functions receiving them creating them
接收它们的函数创建它们
and returning them as well so that gives
并把它们还给我们
us an ability to program with
我们有编程能力
higher-order functions where you are
您所在的高阶函数
raising your bar you're saying I'm not
提高你的水平，你是说我不是
only going to receive objects from you
只会收到你的东西
or data from you or primitives from you
或您的数据或您的原始数据
I'm also willing to receive functions
我也很愿意接受功能
from you as well that's basically what
基本上也是你的意思
higher-order functions give us well this
高阶函数很好地做到了这一点
leads just to some really powerful
导致一些真正强大的
things and to me while I'm really
和我在一起的时候
excited about immutability while I'm
我对不变性感到兴奋
really excited about you know
你真的很兴奋
higher-order functions but to me these
高阶函数，但对我来说这些
are not the most important things to
不是最重要的事情
really work on for example if somebody
真的可以工作，例如有人
comes to you and says hey what's really
来找你说真的
so cool about object-oriented
面向对象真酷
programming
程式设计
I'm not suggesting object or programming
我不是在建议对象或编程
is the one that introduced all of these
是介绍所有这些的
but
但
what is really cool about object into
对象真正酷的是什么
programming well we could say that
编程很好，我们可以这样说
object of programming is where we really
编程的对象是我们真正的地方
honor abstraction right sure absolutely
荣誉抽象权利绝对肯定
and then we honor encapsulation so
然后我们尊重封装
absolutely we want really to really fill
绝对我们要真正填补
in for some capsulation and then of
进行一些封装，然后
course we want to really have
当然我们真的想要
inheritance and then of course what is
继承，然后当然是什么
the last thing polymorphism but if you
最后是多态性，但是如果你
really think about it in among these
真的在其中考虑
four things which is the most important
最重要的四件事
thing so polymorphism which is the most
最多态的东西
important thing well abstraction is not
重要的是抽象不是
new to object into programming at all
完全反对编程
we've been doing abstraction for many
我们已经为许多人做了抽象
many series even before we thought of
很多系列，甚至在我们想到之前
programming right
编程权
Plato introduce the concept of
柏拉图介绍了
abstraction if not being one of the
如果不是其中之一则抽象
first definitely one of the first people
首先肯定是最早的人之一
to do this we've been using abstraction
为此，我们一直在使用抽象
every single thing we do in every
我们在每一件事中所做的每一件事
language we have ever written we have
我们曾经写过的语言
abstraction some form or the other maybe
抽象某种形式或其他
lot not all languages give us the user
并非所有的语言都给我们用户
defining the datatypes but we can say
定义数据类型，但是我们可以说
that's great we can have that well so
太好了，我们可以做得很好
discard that encapsulation well sure
一定要丢弃该封装
encapsulation is extremely important but
封装非常重要，但
you could do encapsulation even within a
您甚至可以在
function whatever local variable you put
功能无论您放置什么局部变量
in a function is encapsulated right so
在一个函数中被封装了，所以
this really extends and gives you other
这真的延伸，给你其他
forms of encapsulation that's absolutely
绝对的封装形式
useful I'm not saying it's not useful
我不是说这没用
but I'm not going to oh just because I
但是我不会因为我而去
can do encapsulation sure that's
可以做封装确保
extremely welcoming
非常热情
what about inheritance the only thing we
继承是唯一的问题吗
inherit is pain because in this case you
继承是痛苦的，因为在这种情况下，您
mostly this is really a cause of problem
大多数情况下这确实是问题的原因
than a cause of strength there's really
不仅仅是力量的原因
a good variety of object under languages
语言下的各种对象
that don't even care about inheritance
甚至都不在乎继承
unfortunately when we program in one
不幸的是，当我们在一个程序中编程时
language predominantly they blind us and
语言主要是他们使我们蒙蔽
they sincerely do unfortunately because
他们真心遗憾地因为
they really blind us we're not able to
他们真的使我们蒙蔽了我们
think beyond it this is one of the
认为这是其中之一
reasons I really want to learn different
我真的想学习不同的原因
languages that way I would not think
我不会想到的那种语言
about anything in one particular way
以某种特定方式处理任何事情
right so there's no one real way to
对，所以没有一种真正的方法
think about things there's so many
想想事情太多了
variations inheritance is not really
变异继承不是真的
required in a lot of lot of ways and
在很多方面都需要
it's usually part of a problem than a
它通常是问题的一部分，而不是
solution most of the time but that
大部分时间都可以解决，但是
leaves this polymorphism though
尽管保留了这种多态性
polymorphism is not unique to object
多态性并非对象独有
under programming
正在编程中
I really do poly object programming for
我真的为
polymorphic behaviors because this is
多态行为，因为这是
what gives me extensibility in my
是什么让我的扩展性
software so to me
软件对我来说是如此
but oh really what is it we are really
但是哦，那真的是什么，我们真的
after polymorphism is to object-oriented
多态性是面向对象之后
programming so this is what I'm really
编程所以这就是我真正的
really after when it comes to
真的在谈到
programming a polymorphism means to
编程多态性意味着
object of programming as and what am I
编程的对象以及我是什么
really going forward so similarly when
真的如此向前迈进
it comes to functional programming what
关于函数式编程
do people normally tell us well they
人们通常告诉我们他们
tell us in the functional programming
在函数式编程中告诉我们
world immutability is extremely
世界的不可改变性
important this is like saying
重要，这就像在说
abstraction and encapsulation all those
所有这些抽象和封装
good stuff similarly they tell us that
好东西，他们告诉我们
higher-order functions are really
高阶函数真的
important oh yeah absolutely I
重要哦，是的，我绝对
completely agree with that higher-order
完全同意那个高阶
functions are important but but the real
功能固然重要，但真正的
charming feature of functional
功能的迷人之处
programming in my opinion really comes
我认为编程真的来了
from two things one is function
从两件事来看，一是功能
composition and the other is lazy
组成，另一个很懒
evaluation so these are the two most
评估，所以这是两个最重要的
charming features our functional
迷人的功能，我们的功能
programming and this is what I wake up
编程，这就是我醒来的
every morning to enjoy when it comes to
每天早晨享受
functional programming these to me are
对我来说，函数式编程是
the pathway to get me to this I cannot
我无法做到的途径
do this without these two but I'm not
没有这两个就做，但是我不是
doing these two without getting these
做这两个而没有得到这些
two right that's what I'm really after
二是我真正追求的
so I'm gonna say function composition
所以我要说功能组成
and lazy evaluation is to functional
懒惰的评估对功能
programming because that's what we
编程，因为那就是我们
really are after in in terms of what we
就我们而言，确实是在追求
are our goals are to to cherish as an
我们的目标是珍惜
important feature
重要特征
why because function composition gives
为什么因为功能组合给
us expressive code it's able to be able
我们具有表现力的代码
to really express the code as a series
真正将代码表达为一系列
of transformations it removes accidental
它消除了偶然的转变
complexity the reason are not happy with
复杂性原因不满意
imperative code is because of the
命令性代码是因为
complexity it brings them the accidental
复杂性给他们带来了意外
complexity it brings into the code
它带来了代码的复杂性
whereas the function composition that
而功能组成
removes that accidental complexity it
消除了意外的复杂性
makes the code expressive it makes the
使代码更具表现力
code easier to follow it makes the code
代码更容易遵循，这使得代码
easier to understand and that is one of
更容易理解，这是其中之一
the biggest gains I get out of it but
我从中获得最大的收获，但是
unfortunately though I cannot just sell
不幸的是，尽管我不能卖掉
you that function composition is great
你说功能组合很棒
and go home because you're gonna go try
回家吧，因为你要去尝试
it and say are you a idiot because this
并说你是白痴，因为这
is going to create objects after objects
将要在对象之后创建对象
after objects and we could have really
在对象之后，我们可能真的
problem the more garbage you crew
问题是您的船员越垃圾
the more garbage you have to collect and
您必须收集更多的垃圾，
we're not going to have good performance
我们不会有好的表现
for large data set if we keep creating
如果我们继续创建大型数据集
objects but in all fairness there's a
对象，但公平地说，有一个
lot of languages that do just exactly
许多语言完全可以做到
that they give you the functional style
他们给你的函数式风格
the function composition but they do not
功能组成，但它们不
give you the lazy evaluation in those
给你那些懒惰的评价
languages when you create a large
创建大型语言时
collection and go through a function
收集并通过功能
pipeline you will create a lot of
管道，您将创建很多
intermediate collections along the way
一路上的中间收藏
but they don't seem to care about it for
但他们似乎并不在乎
a couple of reasons because most of the
有几个原因，因为大多数
time people you work with really small
和你一起工作的人很少
collections
馆藏
it doesn't hurt performance and again
它不会再次损害性能
pragmatically speaking I don't want to
务实地说，我不想
complain about things that don't affect
抱怨不影响的事情
me hey my collections are really small
我嘿，我的收藏很小
the performance is reasonable why bother
性能合理，为什么要打扰
be happy about it but I'm personally
对此感到高兴，但我个人
working on large data projects these are
在大数据项目上工作的是
these days I deal with millions of data
这些天我处理数百万个数据
performance is the most important thing
性能是最重要的
everything else comes after that having
一切都在那之后
the laziness gives a way to really be
懒惰使人真正成为
efficient and expressive at the same
高效而富有表现力的
time that's one of the really because
时间是真正的原因之一
benefits we get out of it so in other
我们从中受益，在其他方面
words the immutability and the
不变性和
higher-order functions are really nice
高阶函数真的很好
very useful very critical but where what
非常有用，非常关键，但是在哪里
I'm really after is is those two
我真的是那两个
function composition and lazy evaluation
功能组成和懒惰评估
that's what I'm really really after when
那才是我真正的想法
it comes to these languages what does
这些语言有什么作用
this really help us what does the purity
这真的对我们有帮助吗？
help us with and and let's understand
帮助我们，让我们了解
how this can be very useful I love
我爱这怎么会很有用
languages for what they do because when
语言是做什么的，因为什么时候
languages know that a certain construct
语言知道某种结构
is very pure
很纯净
there are optimizations languages can do
有语言可以做的优化
let's take a look at an example of this
让我们来看一个例子
real quickly one such language is
很快，一种这样的语言是
Haskell our Haskell is probably one of
Haskell我们的Haskell可能是其中之一
the languages that really amazes me
真正令我惊讶的语言
because I actually rejected the language
因为我实际上拒绝了该语言
a few times I tried to learn it three
几次我试图学习它三
times I gave up every single time and
每次我放弃的时间
the third time I sat down and said you
我第三次坐下来对你说
know all my friends tell me it's a good
知道我所有的朋友告诉我，这很好
thing I trust them I want to learn it
我相信他们的事我想学习
and here's what I had really hard time
这就是我真的很难过的
learning Haskell every single time I sat
我每次坐都学习Haskell
down to learn Haskell I was trying to go
去学习Haskell，我想去
through the the static typing and I
通过静态输入，我
could I'm not smart enough to even get
我不够聪明甚至无法得到
it and I just can't get get failing
它，我就是失败了
every time and then one day I realized
每当有一天，我意识到
oh my gosh I've been doing this wrong
哦，天哪，我做错了
Haskell cares less
Haskell不在乎
about me telling what the type is it's a
关于我告诉它是什么类型的
language that has a very powerful type
具有非常强大的类型的语言
inference it can figure out what the
推断它可以找出
type is very smartly and here I was
类型非常聪明，我在这里
trying to tell it every single detail
试图告诉每个细节
and I'm trying to really hurt myself and
我正试图伤害自己，
I nowadays I don't put any type at all
如今我根本不放任何类型
mostly when I write Haskell code it
主要是当我编写Haskell代码时
doesn't seem to care and we're really
似乎不在乎，我们真的
good friends now and that's not the way
好朋友，现在不是这样
we started out so the beautiful thing
我们开始就这么美丽
about this is the language is actually
关于这是语言实际上
very powerful in that regard but I want
在这方面非常强大，但我想要
you to think about one thing
你想一件事
defaults and there are languages this is
默认值，这是一些语言
purely a language fundamental right
纯粹是语言的基本权利
there are languages that do save
有些语言可以保存
defaults and then there are languages
默认值，然后有语言
that do unsaved defaults so I really
没有保存默认值，所以我真的
spend a tiny bit of time thinking about
花一点时间思考
it look at languages like Haskell it's
看像Haskell这样的语言
save defaults everything is pure if you
如果您保存默认设置，那么一切都是纯净的
want to make something impure you have
想要使你有不纯净的东西
to beg and say please this one time
求求你说一次
please only this afternoon let me make
请只在今天下午让我做
this impure and Haskell will say not
这种不纯洁，Haskell会说不
today and it's like really really really
今天，就像真的真的真的
hard to make things impure right you
很难使事情变得不正确
have to work extra hard to do it you
必须加倍努力才能做到这一点
know languages like Java everything is
知道Java之类的语言
unsafe mostly you want to go to Java and
不安全主要是您想去Java和
say could I please make this immutable
说我能不能使这个不变
this time please this time and Java says
这次请这次，Java说
ok I'll think about it so it's a
好吧，我会考虑的，这是一个
complete office opposite spectrum of
对面的完整办公室
where things are isn't it and and in
那里不是那里和那里
that case when a language can enforce
一种语言可以强制执行的情况
purity there are things it can do I'll
纯度有些事情我可以做
just give you one example of this where
只是给你一个例子
just to share an excitement I have
只是为了分享我的兴奋
witness let's say I have an ad function
见证人，说我有一个广告功能
where ad a B this is a Haskell code is a
如果广告B是Haskell代码，
plus B well cured this is a very simple
加B好治好这是很简单的
example a plus B but there is something
例如加号B但有一些东西
that Haskell knows that languages like
Haskell知道像
Java would never know and that is
Java永远不会知道，那就是
Haskell knows that this is a pure
Haskell知道这是纯粹的
function because variables are immutable
功能，因为变量是不可变的
in Haskell by by default you cannot
默认情况下，在Haskell中，您不能
change them and as a result Haskell
更改它们，结果Haskell
knows that this is a pure function if
知道这是一个纯函数，如果
you write the same code in Java Java
您在Java中编写相同的代码Java
says I gosh I don't know what you're
说我天哪，我不知道你是什么
doing in these functions I can't
在这些功能中我做不到
guarantee purity at this point a could
在这一点上保证纯度
change elsewhere B could change
改变其他地方B可能改变
elsewhere
别处
I can guarantee that for you then I'm
我可以保证，那么我
gonna say over here in this case let's
在这种情况下要在这里说
say I'm gonna say oh let's say evaluate
说我要说哦，让我们说评估
value equals value again a really stupid
价值再次等于价值，真是愚蠢
silly example
愚蠢的例子
then I'm going to say Maine right here
那我要在这里说缅因州
and in the Maine is when I'm gonna
而在缅因州，当我要
introduce some impurity and this is
引入一些杂质，这是
basically saying hey I really want a
基本上是说嘿，我真的想要一个
sequential execution of this code
依次执行此代码
I got dependency on the ordering stuff
我依赖订购的东西
like that so in this case I'm gonna go
这样，在这种情况下，我要去
ahead go to a print and then I'm gonna
前进去打印，然后我要
say evaluate and then I'm gonna pass
说评估，然后我会通过
through it and add one and three well a
通过它并添加一个和三个以及一个
very simple example as you can see but
您可以看到一个非常简单的示例，但是
when I run this code it produces a value
当我运行此代码时，它会产生一个值
of 4
共4
but languages like Haskell can do
但是像Haskell这样的语言可以做到
something really different than other
确实与众不同
languages in the case of Haskell there
Haskell的语言
are two distinctive evaluation models
是两个独特的评估模型
one is called the normal order and the
一种叫做正常秩序，
other is called the applicative order so
其他被称为适用令
applicative order and in this case a
适用命令，在这种情况下
java and most of the languages we are
Java和我们大多数的语言
used to do what is called the
曾经做过所谓的
applicative order you know it's really
您知道这是真的
funny we call it normal order because
有趣的是，我们称其为正常顺序，因为
it's pretty abnormal very few languages
非常少见的语言
actually do this in reality in a normal
实际上是在正常情况下做到这一点
order functions are evaluated not in the
订单函数的计算不在
order in which you apply them so if you
您应用它们的顺序，如果您
were to look at this in your eyes of
要在你的眼中看这个
Java program if I asked you when will ad
Java程式，如果我问您何时会刊登广告
be called
叫做
you tell me ad is going to be called
你告诉我广告将被称为
right away because and it's going to be
马上，因为这将是
called right away and the result of ad
立即被调用和广告的结果
is going to be sent evaluate and the
将要发送评估和
result evaluate is going to be Haskell
结果评估将是Haskell
says never mind aren't gonna call ad
说没关系不会打广告
what are you gonna do with AD well gosh
你会怎么做与AD好天哪
I'm gonna send it to evaluate what I'm
我要发送它来评估我
gonna do with the evaluate I'm gonna
我要去做评估
send it to print okay that's a good
发送打印好吗
reason to do it
这样做的理由
it's absolutely lazy right and it
这绝对是懒惰吧，它
postpones it but it can postpone it
推迟但可以推迟
because I had one and three will never
因为我只有一三个不会
give you a different result in a million
给你一百万的不同结果
years it's pure and that's one of the
年，它是纯净的，这是其中之一
properties of pure functions it's gonna
纯函数的性质
give you the result the same result
给你同样的结果
every single time you call so I want to
每次您打电话时，我想
prove to you that this is actually not
向您证明这实际上不是
going to call ad you know until you
会打给您知道的广告，直到您
really need it
真的需要它
how do I prove it well in the case of
我该如何证明
job I often put a print statement if I
如果我我经常做一份打印声明
put a print statement Haskell it kind of
放一份Haskell的打印声明
scares that minces are really you're
剁碎的恐惧真的是你
trying to do this so I can't do this I
试图做到这一点，所以我做不到
never thought I would use a debugger to
没想到我会使用调试器
prove a point I feel it enough shame so
证明一点，我感到很羞耻，所以
pardon me for doing that so in this case
在这种情况下，请原谅我这样做
I'm gonna go ahead and stay over here
我要去这里住
just bring up the GHC i and this is a if
刚提出GHC我，这是一个如果
I know how to type GHC I so this is the
我知道如何键入GHC，所以这是
repple that I'm gonna use for Haskell
我要用于Haskell的repple
and I'm gonna say
我要说
load here the sample sample dot HS and
在此处加载样本样本点HS和
I'm gonna just blue load this file here
我要在这里蓝色加载此文件
then I'm gonna say break I'm gonna put a
然后我要说休息我要放一个
breakpoint on line number one character
第一行字符上的断点
number 16 so I'm gonna say 1 and 16 well
16号，所以我要说1和16
now that I put a breakpoint I'm gonna
现在我设置了一个断点
call the main function well as you would
很好地调用主函数
see here it is waiting for me on line
看到这里在线等着我
number 1 at character 11 and 15 it says
字符11和15的数字1表示
I'm gonna wait for this and okay thank
我要等待，谢谢
you for waiting
你等待
continue and she or it gave the reserved
继续，她或它给了保留
a for I didn't really prove a whole lot
因为我并没有真正证明很多
right now did I well let's come back to
现在我很好，让我们回到
this but I'm gonna go back to this code
这个，但我要回到这段代码
and say when you call evaluate value
并说出当您致电评估价值时
equals I'm gonna return a 42 when I run
等于我跑步时要返回42
the code notice that I surf this 42 but
代码注意到我在这冲浪42
Haskell is very smart
Haskell非常聪明
Haskell says what do you want to do you
Haskell说您想做什么
say Haskell call add it says why because
说Haskell电话加上它说为什么，因为
of what a pass the result to evaluate
评估结果合格的程度
why because I want to print it okay
为什么，因为我要打印好
let's just print the result of evaluate
让我们只打印评估结果
it comes in at runs evaluate reevaluate
它在运行时评估重新评估
returns 42 notice you never cared about
返回42个您从未关心的通知
value and Haskell say is gosh why do I
价值和Haskell说，天哪，我为什么
waste time doing stuff that has no
浪费时间做没有的事情
meaning I don't have to really waste my
意思是我不必真的浪费我的
time let's be lazy but laziness becomes
时间让我们变得懒惰，但是懒惰变得
from purity so I'm gonna show to you
纯粹，所以我要向你展示
that ad was never called but how do we
该广告从未被调用过，但是我们该如何
prove that ad was never called well that
证明广告从未被很好地调用过
actually turns out to be really easy
事实证明真的很容易
after all because if I go back here and
毕竟因为如果我回到这里
run the GHC i again go back can put the
运行GHC我再次回去可以把
breakpoint one more time on that line
在那条线上再断点一次
but this time it called the main method
但这一次它称为main方法
and in this case of course oops sorry
在这种情况下当然抱歉
I've missed appear let me try this again
我错过了出现，让我再试一次
so in this case of course I'm gonna go
所以在这种情况下我当然要走了
back try again so let's go ahead and say
返回再试一次，让我们继续说
load the file again so I'm gonna load
再次加载文件，所以我要加载
the file let's load the sample dot HS
该文件让我们加载样本点HS
got it let's put a breakpoint on line
知道了，让我们在断点上
116 I'm gonna call the main function and
116我要调用主函数
notice it never ever stopped on the add
注意它从未停止过添加
function well that's really
运作良好，真的
optimizations that can come through when
何时可能发生的优化
a language begins to know that you are
一种语言开始知道你是
following honoring purity of functions
遵循功能纯正
and and this goes a long way so purity
而且这很长一段路要走
is really the reason I want to do it'll
真的是我想要这样做的原因
keep things pure and follow these things
保持事物纯洁并遵循这些事物
is because of greater efficiency I get
是因为我得到了更高的效率
out of it and that is really the
出来的，那真的是
motivating factor for me to really go
推动我前进的因素
towards that well that brings up the
朝着那个井，
question then if functional
然后问是否功能正常
purity is so important how in the world
纯度是如此重要
can we make those things happen
我们能使那些事情发生吗
you know if I'm programming in Java you
你知道我在用Java编程吗
have to work extra hard to make these
必须加倍努力才能使这些
things work because the language may not
之所以有效，是因为该语言可能无法
be there to safeguard you all the time
一直在保护你
you have to have fairly good code
你必须有相当好的代码
reviews you have to have other tools
评论您必须拥有其他工具
that check for these things you may have
检查您可能拥有的这些东西
to do a little bit more work in terms of
在以下方面做更多的工作
determining these things so how do we go
确定这些事情，我们该如何去
about doing this well one of the things
做好这件事之一
I want you to think about is when you
我要你想的是当你
write functions as much as you can make
编写尽可能多的函数
those functions pure so this is
这些功能纯净，所以这是
something you and I can actually do one
你和我实际上可以做的一件事
way actually we can help doing it is to
实际上我们可以帮助您做到的是
keep the functions relatively short some
保持功能相对简短一些
people have the tendency to write very
人们倾向于非常写作
long functions long methods long methods
长函数长方法长方法
are evil in several several ways and
在几种方面是邪恶的，
long methods are really hard to prove
长方法真的很难证明
what nefarious things they are doing
他们在做什么邪恶的事情
under the hood
引擎盖下
so you definitely want to keep methods
所以你绝对想保留方法
really short so it's easier to examine
真的很短，所以更容易检查
them and show that we can also use tools
并表明我们也可以使用工具
that can verify for purity as well but
也可以验证纯度，但是
when it comes to purity of functions we
当涉及到功能的纯净性时，我们
have to really enforce purity and and I
必须真正实现纯洁，而我
and the reason this is so critical like
原因如此关键
I mentioned is because you cannot get
我提到的是因为你无法得到
better performance without having the
更好的性能而无需
purity of functions so this is why it
功能纯正，这就是为什么
becomes absolutely critical but from the
变得绝对关键，但从
point of view practical wise how is it
从实用角度来看如何
practical to achieve this well the very
实际做到这一点非常
first thing is when you write methods
首先是当您编写方法时
make sure those methods that you are
确保您使用的是这些方法
writing a as much as possible are pure I
尽量写一个纯我
came into work one fine morning and and
一个好的早晨开始工作，并且
a buddy of mine said hey the code worked
我的一个伙伴说，嘿，代码行得通
really well sequentially but took a lot
顺序确实很好，但是花了很多
of time to run I made it parallel I
运行时间我使它平行
don't even have to tell you what the
甚至不必告诉你
result was it what the speed was the
结果是速度是多少
result is wrong and and yeah but the
结果是错误的，是的，但是
result is wrong it doesn't matter how
结果是错误的，没关系
fast you got the wrong result isn't it
很快，你得到了错误的结果，不是吗
so I immediately said you know what I
所以我立刻说你知道我
haven't looked at the code yet but I can
还没有看过代码，但是我可以
tell you what's happening you have a
告诉你发生了什么事
variable somewhere and it's a field in
某个地方的变量，这是一个字段
your class you're calling a method and
您的课程中，您正在调用方法，
the method is mutating that field and
该方法正在改变那个领域，
each tear some name says so that's it ha
每个眼泪都有一个名字说，就是这样哈
your wisdom is like yep that's it now
你的智慧就像是
the fun is to go find that out and we
有趣的是去发现它，我们
started just looking through the code
开始只是看代码
and sure enough 30 minutes later we find
并且肯定在30分钟后，我们发现
exactly that one little variable being
正是那个小变量
mutated in this one function
在这一功能中发生了变异
about an hour to refactor the code we
大约一个小时来重构我们的代码
run it we get parallel results much
运行它，我们得到的并行结果很多
faster of course incorrect and and
当然更快不正确，并且
immutability really makes it hard to
不变性真的很难
make it parallel as well so lazy
使其平行也是如此
evaluation and parallel requires purity
评估和并行需要纯度
of functions well if that is the case
如果是这样的话，功能很好
how could we really achieve this
我们如何真正实现这一目标
practically in a program so when it
实际上是在程序中
comes to designing a fab
来设计晶圆厂
application I I try to use the slogan of
应用二尝试使用的口号
a circle of purity but the ring of
一个纯净的圆圈，但
impurity around it so what what I mean
周围的杂质，所以我的意思是
by that is I'm going to take a circle
通过那个我要绕一圈
and I'm gonna say everything in the
我要说的是
circle is going to be pure so it I'll
圆圈将是纯净的，所以我会
build a library of functions and these
建立功能库，这些
library of functions will all guarantee
功能库将全部保证
purity for me and when I'm in this
对我来说纯洁，当我在这里
library of functions within the circle
圈子内的函数库
that circle of purity I will not mutate
我不会改变那纯洁的圈子
any variable I will not mutate any
任何变量我都不会突变
global state I will not mutate any value
全局状态，我不会改变任何值
given to me I'm not going to touch on
给我，我不会谈
and change the state I take an input and
并更改状态我接受输入
return an output that's what I'm gonna
返回我要的输出
do and around the circle of purity I'll
并围绕纯净的圈子我会
build a very thin ring of impurity and
建立一个非常细的杂质环
the stinking ring of impurity is where I
臭臭的环是我的所在
would read from a data base if I want to
如果我想从数据库中读取
I'll do logging I might do work like for
我会记录日志，我可能会这样做
example talking to a web service so a
与Web服务对话的示例
lot of things I can do in the ring of
我可以做的很多事情
impurity but the minute I grab the data
杂质，但是我抓到数据的那一刻
that I want to work with from moving
我想和我一起工作
forward once I enter the circle of
一旦我进入
purity
纯度
I will not mutate anything and I will
我不会变异任何东西，我会
wait until I exit the circle of purity
等到我退出纯洁的圈子
and then once I get out of the circle of
然后一旦我走出
purity I can start mutating things again
纯粹，我可以再次开始变异
because practically the language like
因为实际上这种语言就像
Java does not have this concept of hey
Java没有这个概念嘿
we're going to really enforce you know
我们将真正强制您知道
immutability for you we have to build
不变性为您，我们必须建立
that around with the limitations that we
围绕着我们的局限性
are gonna have in languages like this so
会有这样的语言，所以
having that model of purity versus
有那种纯洁的模型与
impurity where a circle of purity is
纯度为一圈的杂质
where I'm not going to really cause
我不会真正导致的地方
anything impure when it comes to this
关于这个的任何不纯
purity as well we have to be careful not
纯度也要小心
only to not mutate variables but not
只是不变异变量，而不是
also to depend on variables that would
也要取决于将
otherwise be mutable so that's one thing
否则是易变的，这是一回事
we can do in terms of this of however
我们可以在这方面做
there's one major concern we all want to
我们都想关注一个主要问题
as programmers and that is if I'm going
作为程序员，那就是如果我要
to do immutability one way I can do a
做不变性的一种方法
mute
静音
we used to copy objects well wait a
我们过去经常复制对象，等等
minute if I'm gonna copy objects isn't
我要复制对象的分钟不是
that gonna be silly because we're gonna
那会很傻，因为我们要
end up with a large number of objects
最终带有大量物体
and that would be not very good in
在那将不是很好
performance at all so how do we really
性能，那么我们如何真正
put it well this is where we can enjoy
说得好，这是我们可以享受的地方
from some what I would like to call as
从一些我想称呼为
functional data structures for example
例如功能数据结构
if you really think about lists if you
如果你真的考虑清单，如果你
will the list in languages like Clojure
将以Clojure等语言列出
and Scala the lists are completely
和Scala的列表是完全
immutable so you cannot modify a list
不可变，因此您无法修改列表
once you created so immutable but when
一旦你创造了那么一成不变，但是当
you look at a list these lists all
你看一个清单这些清单全部
sufficiently provide certain operations
充分提供某些操作
where you can add elements to the head
您可以在其中添加元素的头部
well it's not it's not mutable but what
好吧，这不是可变的，而是什么
does it mean to add well when you go to
是否意味着您去时要增加好
a list and you add here's an example of
列表，然后添加以下示例
a Scala code if you have a list let's
Scala代码（如果有列表）
say of one two and three let's call it
说一二三
as val list is equal to now you can
因为val list等于现在，您可以
simply say zero and then you can put a
只需说零，然后您就可以
list into it and this will be let's say
列出它，这可以说
list two that you get out of this
列出你从中得到的两个
well list one is immutable list two is a
好清单一是不可变的清单二是一
copy that you get from this given list
复制您从给定列表中获得的内容
and as a result what did they actually
结果，他们实际上做了什么
do here's a very interesting way to
这样做是一种非常有趣的方式
think about how this works imagine that
想想这是如何运作的
the list of people on the front row
前排的人员列表
imagine that list is immutable I cannot
想象清单是一成不变的，我不能
change that list what I can walk up to
改变那个清单我可以走到哪里
the front of the list and declare myself
列表的最前面并声明自己
as the first person in the list with all
作为列表中的第一个人
respect they cannot do anything about it
尊重他们对此无能为力
and and so I because the list is
我之所以这样，是因为清单是
immutable I can declare as myself as the
一成不变，我可以宣称自己是
first person in the list and if you ask
列表中的第一人称，如果您问
the gentleman over there how many people
那边的绅士有多少人
are in your list he's probably gonna say
在您的清单中，他可能会说
I have five people in my list but if you
我的名单上有五个人，但是如果你
ask me I'll say I have six people in my
问我，我会说我有六个人
list because I'm generously going to
列出，因为我很乐意
share the list that's there and that's
分享那里的清单，那是
exactly what these languages do they
这些语言到底是什么
share existing data because the data is
共享现有数据，因为该数据是
immutable
一成不变的
they can do that effectively but of
他们可以有效地做到这一点，但是
course you're adding to the head and
当然，您要添加到头部和
potentially removing from the head to
可能从头部移到
collect a create another list well if
收集一个创建另一个列表，如果
I'm always adding and removing to the
我一直在添加和删除
head what kind of data structure is that
头是什么样的数据结构
well that's obviously a stack so a lot
好吧，这显然是很多东西
of stack based algorithms fit really
基于堆栈的算法非常适合
nicely into this and and similarly what
很好地进入了这个
you can actually do is use
你实际上可以做的就是使用
structures like trice a gentleman named
像崔斯这样的结构绅士
Phil Bagwell created this and a trice is
菲尔·巴格韦（Phil Bagwell）创造了这个
a data structure with a very large
具有非常大的数据结构
branching factor and with the tries
分支因子和尝试
essentially these are called persistent
本质上，这些被称为持久性
data structures and it's called
数据结构，它被称为
persistent because they are immutable
持久的，因为它们是不可变的
you're not going to change it twice
你不会改变它两次
itself was not immutable but Ritchie
本身不是一成不变的，但里奇
submitted enclosure and suggested that
提交附件并建议
we can actually make use of it but
我们实际上可以利用它，但是
because of a very heavy branching factor
由于非常重的分支因子
the cost of making changes are creating
进行变更的成本正在增加
a copy if you will is extremely small
如果您愿意的话，副本很小
Ricky calls this as effectively constant
Ricky将此称为有效常数
or are practically constant well it's
或者实际上是恒定不变的
practically constant because it's order
实际上是恒定的，因为它是有序的
of let's say a log n where the order of
假设log n的顺序
log n but the log of n in this case is n
log n，但在这种情况下n的对数为n
is not the number of elements n is the
不是元素的数量n是
number of levels if you will so in this
级别数（如果您愿意）
case of course if you have four levels
当然，如果您有四个级别
because the branching factor is really
因为分支因子真的
huge a branching factor is when you can
一个巨大的分支因素是什么时候可以
have many number of children tries
有很多儿童尝试
usually have thirty-two or more children
通常有32个或更多的孩子
within a four level you can literally
在四个级别内，您可以按字面意思
pack more than a million elements and to
打包了超过一百万个元素
make a copy of that particular million
复制该特定的百万
elements collection you are going to
您要去的元素集合
spend an order of log four which is
花一个订单四的日志是
practically a constant I ran some
几乎是恒定的，我跑了一些
examples with this I took the vector
这个例子我带了矢量
which is in Scala which is a price
在斯卡拉，这是一个价格
implementation ran it from within Java
实现从Java内部运行
and I found out for a hundred thousand
我发现了十万
elements the cost of creating a new one
元素创建一个新的成本
where I changed something right in the
我在其中更改了一些内容
middle was something like 33 33
中间大概是33 33
nanoseconds and it's been a few years
十亿分之一秒
since I ran this actually but it can be
因为我实际上已经运行了，但是可以
really really fast as well so we can
真的非常快，所以我们可以
start using some of these ideas but if
开始使用其中一些想法，但如果
you really have to poke the data
你真的必须戳数据
eventually that's where the circle of
最终那是
purity was a circle of impurity the
纯度是一圈杂质
circle of purity versus the ring of
纯度环与环
impurity can come in really effectively
杂质可以真正有效地进入
but there's one other issue that we have
但是还有一个问题
to deal with we have to think in
处理，我们必须考虑
functional style for this a
这个的函数式风格
recommendation is to think declaratively
建议以声明方式思考
first and then you are saying well now
首先，然后你现在说得很好
that I know how to X was the problem in
我知道如何X是问题所在
words I'm gonna try to try to write
我要尝试写的单词
functions for it the JDK has a slew of
JDK有很多功能
methods that can help us with this there
在那里可以帮助我们的方法
are so many methods in the JDK that we
JDK中有很多方法，我们
can use to do these kinds of
可以用来做这些
transformations you can take a
您可以进行转换
collection in
收集在
from memory you can take a files content
从内存中可以获取文件内容
and you can start looping through them
您可以开始遍历它们
you know in a functional style so
你知道功能性的风格
there's a lot of different things you
你有很多不同的事情
can do with functional style of
可以做到的函数式风格
programming and as you start writing
编程以及开始写作时
code itself to ask the question how do i
编码自己问这个问题我该怎么办
express this in functional style but
用函数式风格表达
last thing I want to cover is one very
我想讲的最后一件事是
sticky point and that is exceptions and
症结是例外
I'm sure many of us have felt that pain
我敢肯定我们很多人都感到那种痛苦
right so when you go to a stream for
对，所以当你去溪流
example if you go to a stream let's say
例如，如果你去一个小溪，让我们说
we have a stream with a collection of
我们有一个流的集合
numbers and in this case I want to
数字，在这种情况下，我想
perform a scream
尖叫
operation so what are we going to do
操作，我们该怎么办
numbers dart stream and I'm gonna
数字飞镖流，我要
perform a map operation given an element
给定元素执行映射操作
transform the element let's say and then
转换元素，然后说
I'm gonna say let's say for each and
我要说的是每个
then I'm going to simply print out that
然后我将简单地打印出来
value that's been given to me so given
赋予我的价值
the element I print it out but what is
我将其打印出来的元素是什么
the transform method really going to do
真正要做的变换方法
for me well in the case of a transform
对我来说很不错
method
方法
what if transform was going to give me
如果变革要给我怎么办
an exception well notice in this case
在这种情况下，请注意例外
let's start with baby steps a public
让我们从婴儿的脚步开始
static let's say int transform takes a
静态的说int转换需要一个
number and all it's going to do let's
数字和所有要做的事
say is simply return the number right
说只是简单地返回数字对
now so here is a return number imagine
现在，这是一个返回数字
this is a computation that's gonna take
这将是一个计算
some effort we don't have to worry about
我们不必担心的一些努力
it right now but what if I do something
现在，但是如果我做某事怎么办
like this what if I end up doing if
像这样如果我最终会做的话
number let's say is equal to o let's say
假设数字等于o假设
7 then I'm gonna say throw and new
7那我要说扔和新
exception and I'm gonna throw some kind
例外，我要扔些东西
of an art exception so let's say oops
一个艺术例外，所以让我们说
something went wrong just like we get
就像我们得到了一样，出了点问题
exceptions in our systems right and I'm
我们系统中的异常，我
gonna say that it went wrong well what's
会说错了是什么
going to happen at this point this could
将会在这一点上发生
be a very specific checked exception I
是一个非常具体的检查异常
you know I whatever name you want to
你知道我想要什么名字
provide for it at this point the Java
为此提供Java
compiler gives you an error and it says
编译器给你一个错误，它说
hey you cannot throw an exception from
嘿，你不能从
this code because on line number five
该代码，因为在第五行
you have to say you're throwing an
你必须说你在扔一个
exception this is only going to get
例外，这只会得到
worse as we go through
我们经历的时候更糟
now you say throws exception now what's
现在你说抛出异常现在是什么
going to happen Java now complains on
即将发生Java现在抱怨
line number 14 it turns out a lot of
第14行结果很多
these methods don't deal with checked
这些方法不处理检查
exceptions at all why
完全例外
is that well the functional interface
功能界面好吗
simply does not have the function
根本没有功能
functional interface predicate consumer
功能接口谓词消费者
supplier none of them deal with checks
供应商他们都不处理支票
on one hand you could say gosh they
一方面你可以说天哪，他们
didn't deal with checked exceptions but
没有处理检查的异常，但是
there is actually a really good reason
实际上有一个很好的理由
why they didn't provide checked
他们为什么不提供检查
exception because doing it is actually
例外，因为这样做实际上是
not part of a solution it's part of a
不是解决方案的一部分，而是解决方案的一部分
bigger problem so what do we do about
更大的问题，我们该怎么办
this let's think about this for a second
让我们再考虑一下
if we weren't going to step back to this
如果我们不打算退一步
and say okay I want to really handle
说好吧，我真的要处理
this what do we do some people will
这是我们做什么，有些人会
suggest to you a very dangerous solution
向您建议一个非常危险的解决方案
in my opinion and that is to come in
在我看来，那就是进来
here and paint the exception that really
在这里画出真正的例外
happened you know potentially you're not
发生了，你知道你可能不是
the one throwing this exception maybe
一个抛出这个异常的人
this exception is coming from a lower
这种例外来自下层
level when you're calling that other
打电话给其他人时
method that's blowing up with a checked
被检查掉的方法
exception what do you do well so you
例外，你擅长什么，所以你
probably took this number and you did
大概拿了这个数字，你做了
some other work right you called another
你叫另一个工作
function calculate over here and the
函数在这里计算
calculate function maybe you passed the
计算功能，也许你通过了
number over it and that blew with that
在它上面的数字和那吹
exception so they may suggest to you
例外，所以他们可能会建议你
something like this they may say oh
他们可能会说这样的话哦
here's an idea put and try and a catch
这是一个想法，尝试并抓住
around it and then grab that exception
围绕它，然后抓住那个异常
whatever that exception is and then of
不管那个异常是什么，然后
course then do a wrapper on it new
当然要在上面做一个包装
runtime exception and they will even
运行时异常，他们甚至
give you convenience methods to do this
给你方便的方法来做到这一点
and then wrap it there is a very easy
然后将其包裹起来非常简单
way to describe this this is called a
描述这个的方式称为
bad idea well then why is this a bad
好主意，那这为什么不好
idea well the reason is we didn't really
好主意，原因是我们不是真的
solve the problem we just quieted the
解决问题，我们只是安静了
compiler if you really think about it
编译器，如果您真的考虑过
that's what we did right when to the
那就是我们在
competitor and said be quiet now and the
竞争对手说现在要安静
compiler is like okay I'm happy I won't
编译器就像是，我很高兴我不会
complain the problem did go away the
抱怨问题确实消失了
compiler just quieted out this is a
编译器只是安静下来，这是一个
disaster what is the reason why this is
灾难这是什么原因
a disaster well think about where we are
一场灾难，好好想想我们在哪里
right now we are in a function pipeline
现在我们在功能管道中
now in the function pipeline you might
现在在功能管道中，您可能
have filter over here you might have
在这里过滤你可能有
more filters right here and you might
更多过滤器就在这里，您可能
have other operations like for example
还有其他操作，例如
oh let's say a few other map
哦，再说几张地图
operations who-knows-how-many how long
谁知道多少时间的操作
this function pipeline is going to do
该功能管道将要做
well this is a pipeline you are in right
好吧，这是一条正确的管道
now and when you visualize the pipeline
现在以及当您可视化管道时
look at this as a stream of data flowing
将此视为数据流
through from one stage to another stage
从一个阶段到另一个阶段
to end of the stage now in this pipeline
现在在这个管道中结束阶段
if one of things blow up what do you
如果其中一件事情炸毁了，你怎么办
really do so the problem with exception
真的这样做例外的问题
handling is exception handling oops your
处理是异常处理oops your
call stack I'm gonna go out on a limb
调用堆栈，我要走了
and say exception handling and
并说异常处理和
functional style of programming are not
编程的函数式风格不是
orthogonal or completely disconnected it
正交或完全断开
makes no sense to mix them together in
将它们混合在一起没有任何意义
that context why is this a problem let
那上下文为什么这个问题让
me give you a very stupid example of
我给你一个非常愚蠢的例子
this imagine you are driving on the
想象你在开车
freeway and you are about two miles away
高速公路，您大约两英里远
from your eggs and you have a flat tire
从你的鸡蛋中，你轮胎漏气了
what's the worst thing I can tell you
我能告诉你的最坏的事是什么
I'm going to tell you you had a flat
我要告诉你你有一个公寓
tire now drive in Reverse go back to
轮胎现在在反向行驶中返回
where you came from now dude get out
你从哪里来
safely and pull to the exit right so in
安全地向右驶出出口
other words you always face downstream
换句话说，你总是面对下游
you never go upstream and you don't try
你永远不会上游，你不会尝试
to jump out of the freeway that's not
跳出不是
safe also so think of this as a stream
安全，因此也可以将其视为流
when you're flowing through the stream
当你流过溪流时
you don't exit from the stream
你不会从流中退出
abnormally you still have to exit the
异常地，您仍然必须退出
stream in the bottom so when you have a
流在底部，所以当你有一个
stream where you go upstream to
流向上游
downstream how do you deal with it
下游你如何处理
well the question is how do you deal
好吧，问题是你如何处理
with it with this in java let me say i
用它与此在Java中让我说我
am really a fan of streams I truly love
我真的很喜欢流媒体
streams I am going to tell you that I
流，我要告诉你我
enjoy streams I love it I use it all the
享受溪流，我爱它，我用完了
time but that doesn't mean it's perfect
时间，但这并不意味着它是完美的
so ask the question how does streams
所以问一个问题
handle exceptions they handle exceptions
处理异常他们处理异常
with two beautiful words they're called
有两个漂亮的词，他们被称为
good luck so essentially there's no
祝你好运，所以基本上没有
answer really other languages provide
回答其他语言确实提供的
other solutions but Java quietly said
其他解决方案，但Java悄悄地说
deal with it so there's no really good
处理它，所以没有真正的好
answer how to deal with it so how do you
回答如何处理它，你如何
really deal with exceptions if you're
如果你真的处理异常
going to deal with it well you can go
要好好处理就可以了
the hard way and you can deal with it
艰难的方式，你可以应对
one of them really is so this is the
其中之一的确是这样
difference between the functional
功能上的区别
mindset versus the imperative mindset so
心态与命令式心态
Java 8 streams
Java 8流
doesn't give you a good answer one thing
一件事不能给你一个很好的答案
you could potentially do here s you
你可能会在这里做你
could take on the data well essentially
可以很好地处理数据
what you really want to do is you want
你真正想要做的是你想要
to treat exception or error let's put it
对待异常或错误
as error you want to treat error as
作为错误，您想将错误视为
another form of data that's what you
另一种形式的数据就是你
really want to do it is just another
真的想做的只是另一回事
form of data and things do go wrong
数据形式出现问题
things do go mess up and it's okay
事情确实搞砸了，没关系
you don't want to be smacked on the head
你不想被拍打
when something goes wrong just deal with
当出现问题时，请处理
in a very civil way so what are we gonna
以一种非常文明的方式，我们该怎么办
do in this case well okay I'm flowing
在这种情况下做得很好，我在流动
through this processing the data but
通过这种处理数据，
something went wrong here so I'm gonna
这里出了点问题，所以我要
go push that down as an error so you can
去把它作为错误推下来，这样你就可以
deal with the downstream so in other
处理下游，所以在其他
words but how do you really do this in
话，但你如何真正做到这一点
Java sadly there's no real easy way to
遗憾的是，Java没有真正简单的方法
do it in the streams API because if I
在流API中执行此操作，因为如果我
take this in the streams API well I have
我把它很好地放在流API中
to now create a structure where I have a
现在创建一个我有一个结构
data and I have an error and I want to
数据，我有一个错误，我想
push them down and Java doesn't quite
压低它们，Java不太
give us anything like that there are
给我们这样的东西
other languages that provide constructs
提供构造的其他语言
that deal with these kinds of couples of
处理这些类型的夫妇
data and errors but Java doesn't have
数据和错误，但是Java没有
one so we could maybe look for solutions
一个，所以我们也许可以寻找解决方案
elsewhere and such place where we can
其他地方和我们可以的地方
look for solution is in JavaScript
寻找解决方案在JavaScript中
promises this is exactly what your
保证这正是你的
completable futures in Java do as well
Java中可完成的期货也是如此
because after all completable future in
因为毕竟在未来可以完成
Java is nothing but promises in in a
Java只是承诺
sense so what do completable futures and
感觉如何，可完成的期货和
promises do well completable futures and
许诺做的很好的期货和
promises say well when you have data
有数据时，诺言说得好
will flow the data through in other
将数据通过其他
words the promises and completable
承诺和完成的话
futures I like to say that they have two
我要说的期货有两个
channels and the two channels they have
渠道和他们拥有的两个渠道
is a data channel and then they also
是一个数据通道，然后
have what is called an error channel
有所谓的错误通道
that's the way I view this so in other
我就是这样看的
words this pipeline right off the bat
说这条管道马上
has two channels to work with you have a
有两个与您合作的渠道
data channel and you have a error
数据通道，您有一个错误
channel or you can say it is a right
频道，或者您可以说这是对的
channel and a left channel well as
通道和左通道以及
things go really well
事情进展顺利
you are just transforming through the
你只是通过改变
data Channel or the right channel when
数据通道或右通道时
things really go bad you go to the error
事情真的很糟糕，你去错误
Channel and you deal with it so by by
频道，您可以通过
structure both completable futures and
构造可完成的期货和
promises are built with these two types
这两种类型都建立了承诺
of channels this
的频道数
more elegant in my opinion as a really
在我看来，更优雅
better way to handle it because it
处理它的更好方法，因为它
promotes that model of let's deal with
促进我们应对的模式
things downstream so you give an
下游的东西，所以你给
opportunity for transforming data but
转换数据的机会，但是
you also given opportunity for
您也给了机会
transforming errors as well one of the
转换错误以及其中之一
ways in which this works is if things
它的工作方式是
are going well you keep marching on the
进展顺利，您继续前进
right side if things are not going well
如果事情进展不顺利的话
you come to the left side and you're
你来到左边而你
dealing with an exception but if you're
处理异常，但如果您是
able to handle the error you can go back
能够处理错误，您可以返回
to the right side and so you can really
在右侧，所以您可以真正
recover from errors as well and that
从错误中恢复以及
gives you a really nice way to handle it
给您一个非常好的处理方式
but that unfortunately doesn't answer
不幸的是，这并没有回答
our questions because a promise
我们的问题，因为一个承诺
literally is still zero our one piece of
从字面上看还是零，我们的
data our completable future is a zero or
数据，我们可完成的未来为零或
in piece of data so through a complete
通过完整的数据
one future you may have one data going
将来你可能会有一份数据
through our art none goes through but in
通过我们的艺术，只有通过
a stream you have n pieces of data that
一个流，您有n条数据
go through so you're gonna have n pieces
经过，所以你将有n件
of data that go through you cannot
您无法通过的数据
obviously rely on promises to do it what
显然依靠诺言去做
could we do this is where the observable
我们可以做到这一点吗？
ideas begin to take a bit of a route so
想法开始走一些路，所以
observables are flows depending on what
可观察物是取决于什么的流量
you are using observers are flows really
你正在使用观察者是真的
are kind of like promises except that
有点像诺言，除了
they could be 0 too many pieces of data
他们可能是0太多数据
so one of the things I really like about
所以我最喜欢的一件事
observables is they do have a data
可观察到的是他们确实有数据
channel so just like what we had in the
渠道，就像我们在
other case they have a data channel they
其他情况下他们有一个数据通道
also in addition have the error channel
另外还有错误通道
as well but in addition to it they also
除此之外，他们还
have a third channel which is our
有第三个频道，这是我们的
completable a completed channel so the
完成一个完整的渠道，因此
completed channel is through which you
完成的渠道是您通过它
send a message saying I don't have any
发送一条信息说我没有任何信息
more data so you can do your clean-up
更多数据，以便您可以清理
operations but more important you have
操作，但更重要的是
this again the data channel an error
这再次是数据通道错误
channel through the promises and
通过承诺和渠道
completable futures at most one data or
最多一个数据的可完成期货或
one error go through through the
通过一个错误
observables on the other hand any number
另一方面可观察到的任何数字
of data may go through and of course if
的数据可能会通过，当然，如果
something were to go wrong your error
有什么地方出了错你的错误
channel will carry the error so you
通道将携带错误，因此您
treat error as data just another form of
将错误视为数据只是另一种形式
data and so relying on some of these
数据，因此依赖其中一些
structures gives the opportunity for us
结构为我们提供了机会
to deal with errors downstream rather
在下游处理错误
than trying to disturb the call chain by
而不是试图通过打扰电话链
throwing exceptions so this is one of
引发异常，所以这是其中之一
the
的
I would sincerely think when I start
我会真诚地思考
programming in functional style is we
以函数式风格进行编程是我们
think about my strategy on how I handle
考虑一下我如何处理的策略
with exceptions because fundamentally
有例外，因为从根本上
throwing exceptions is really a it
抛出异常确实是一个问题
doesn't make any sense in the world of
在这个世界上毫无意义
function of style of programming you
编程风格的功能
really want to deal with error as if
真的想像对待错误一样
it's just another form of data and you
这只是另一种数据形式
want to just push it downstream and
只是想将其推向下游，
handle that so this is one of the places
处理，所以这是地方之一
where I normally start with streams on
我通常从流开始
my projects I enjoy streams and I use it
我的项目我喜欢串流，我用它
but when when my project becomes a
但是当我的项目变成
little bit more complex and we have to
稍微复杂一点，我们必须
deal with a fairly complex amount of
处理相当复杂的
exceptions and errors that's when I
我当时的例外与错误
consider really looking at something
考虑真的看东西
like a observable or flowable because
像可观察或可流动的，因为
there's a really better answer in terms
有一个更好的答案
of how we can continue using the flow of
如何继续使用流程
data a stream of data but the data can
数据流，但数据可以
flow through downstream and we can
流过下游，我们可以
handle it and and so that is a
处理它，所以这是一个
rethinking of how we want to handle the
重新思考我们要如何处理
exceptions so to summarize what we
例外，所以总结一下我们
talked about when it comes to functional
谈到功能
style of programming your language like
编程语言的风格，例如
Java give us the ability to write
Java使我们能够编写代码
lambdas they give us the ability to
lambda，它们使我们能够
write streams but that's when the real
写流，但这是真正的
fun starts because we can't just walk in
有趣的开始是因为我们不能只是走进去
and start doing from programming in
并从编程开始
language like Java because there are
Java之类的语言，因为有
other constraints other things we have
其他制约因素
to be really really careful about and
真的要非常小心
and unfortunately keep in mind as as
不幸的是要记住
much as I love what job is doing as much
我非常喜欢这份工作
as the power it gives you it's the
因为它给你的力量是
language that will not protect you all
无法保护所有人的语言
the way through when you're dealing with
与您打交道的方式
in variables and mutability so you have
在变量和可变性方面，
to take the personal responsibility to
承担个人责任
make sure you're honoring immutability
确保您尊重不变性
where it makes sense you have to control
您必须控制的地方
those things and you have to also take a
这些东西，你还必须
stab at dealing with things like
试图处理类似的事情
exception as well in in designing the
设计中的例外
systems and the circular purity and the
系统和循环纯度以及
and the ring of impurity may something
杂质环可能会
help you as well hope that was useful
希望对您有所帮助
thank you
谢谢
[Applause]
[掌声]